Second Lieutenant Viktoriya Serebryakov,
（ヴィーシャ）ヴィクトーリヤ･
セレブリャコーフ少尉
参謀本部の指名により
副官として着任いたしました
reporting in as your assistant
as per Strategic HQ orders.
（ターニャ）
貴官が… 副官？
You're my assistant?
はい 大尉殿と
面識がある上―
Yes.
It seems I was assigned this post because
I already knew you, and we're both women.
同性ということで
配置されたようです
ハッ 上も随分と
気を遣ってくれる
Gee, the brass sure is being
awfully considerate.
Belated congratulations on your promotion,
Second Lieutenant.
ああ 遅まきながら
昇進おめでとう 少尉
Thank you!
ありがとうございます
では 早速―
I'll get to work right away, then!
仕事に取りかからせて
いただきます
やめておけ ２人で
どうにかなる量ではない
Don't bother. This isn't something
two people can handle.
Don't worry.
（ヴィーシャ）ご安心を
衛兵司令に相談済みです
I've already spoken with Garrison Command.
They'll send dozens of unoccupied
MPs and other personnel.
手すきの憲兵などを
ダース単位で手配できます
What?
何？
I wanted to contribute to clearing
the organization work as fast as possible.
（ヴィーシャ）
速やかな編成完了に―
尽力したいと
思いまして
（ターニャ）
優秀すぎる副官も問題だな
Having an assistant who's too talented
is also a problem.
こんなことなら
ライン戦線に―
I should have left her on the Rhine Front!
残しておけばよかった
エヘ…
First Lieutenant Aisha Schubert, reporting in.
（シュルベルツ）
アイシャ･シュルベルツ中尉
ただいま 着任いたしました
First Lieutenant Klein Balhelm, likewise.
（バルハルム）
クレイン･バルハルム中尉
同じく着任いたします
Good to see you.
（ターナー）ご苦労
魔導大隊編成委員長の
I am Colonel Gregorio von Turner, head of
the Mage Battalion Organization Committee.
グレゴリオ･フォン･
ターナー大佐だ
You are to head to
6th Air Squadron Command at once.
諸君らは 直ちに
第６航空戦隊司令部へと
向かいたまえ
But we were told to gather at
this garrison by 1400 today.
あっ しかし
本日の14：00までに
本駐屯地に集合せよとの通達を…
急きょ変更になった
There's been a change of plans.
Th-There has?
そ… そうですか
Also, should you raise any alarm bells
regarding your handling of classified info,
なお 選抜過程における
機密保持資格に疑義が出た場合
you will be punished and returned
to your original unit at once.
即刻 原隊へ処分付きで送り返す
留意せよ
Keep that in mind.
Yes, sir!
"Failure"
Are you sure?
本当にいいんですか？
（ターニャ）フンッ 知らんな
Don't ask me.
Those who fail to notice the plainly obvious
deserve to be returned to their units.
目の前のことも見えぬ無能など
原隊送りが当然だろう
（ヴィーシャ）
でも… もうこれで14組目ですよ
But that's the fourteenth pair.
まったく… ４組くらいは
受かると思っていたが
Jeez...
I was sure at least four of them would pass.
（ヴィーシャ）
実は 先ほど参謀本部から―
Actually, Strategic HQ just sent a demand
that we speed up the selection.
“選抜を急げ”との要請が
Episode Five
My First Battalion
So the creation of the mage battalion
is nothing but propaganda?
（少尉）つまり魔導大隊の設立は
宣伝目的のプロパガンダ
And I'm supposed to shut up and leave?
黙って きびすを返せと？
（ターナー）すまんな
Sorry.
I'm glad to see you're so ambitious.
貴官の意欲は うれしく思う
次の機会があれば志願してくれ
If there's another opportunity,
please volunteer.
（少尉）あ… 分かりました
I understand.
Excuse me.
失礼します
It's an illusion created by
a normal optical spell,
（ターニャ）
一般的な光学系術式による幻影
音声も術式による合成です
and the voice is a magical synthetic.
（ゼートゥーア）貴官が さんざん
不合格を突きつけるのも納得だな
I can see why you keep failing people.
A mage should be able to
see through this easily.
この程度は 魔導師なら
見破れて当然
But out of thirty-nine sets,
ですが
これまで39組中33組が―
thirty-three have been deceived and
sent back to their home units.
だまされて 原隊復帰となりました
Only twelve people have passed.
合格者は わずか12人
中隊分しかありません
That's only enough for a company.
You'll have to lower
the standards for passing.
要求水準を
引き下げるしかあるまい
（ターニャ）では 妥当性のある
基準設定の見直しと―
Then I'll need time for reeducation
and to devise an acceptable new standard.
再教育の時間が必要です
How long, exactly?
具体的には？
A month.
（ターニャ）１か月ほど
（ヴィーシャ）え!?
（将校）たった１か月だと？
Only a month?
（将校）
新兵教育でも ２年はかかるが…
Training a new soldier takes two years.
I don't care.
かまわん この際
多少手荒でも再教育してやれ
Reeducate them, even if you
have to get a little rough.
Roger.
了解しました
（ヴィーシャ）ううっ まさか…
Don't tell me...
Imperial Army Zugspitsche Training Grounds
An enemy attack?
（訓練生）敵襲!?
（訓練生）何が起こった!?
What happened?
I-It's so cold...
（グランツ）うっ… さみぃ…
I figured this would happen.
やっぱり こうなるか…
There's your wake-up call!
（ターニャ）目覚まし代わりだ！
礼には及ばん！
No need for thanks!
I got word that the artillery unit
running exercises in this area
実は 同地で演習中の砲兵隊が―
古い砲弾を持て余しているとの
連絡があってな
had old shells they needed to dispose of.
せっかくだ 砲兵隊と
仲よく遊ぼうではないか
Let's give them a chance for some fun.
なお 誠に残念だが
訓練用弾薬の備蓄は少ないらしい
Also, I'm very sorry to say this,
but they don't have much ammo
stored for the exercise...
せいぜい36時間も撃てば
砲弾も尽きるそうだ
They'll run dry in about
thirty-six hours, maximum.
（ヴァイス）さ… 36時間
Th-Thirty-six hours?
では 始めよう
防衛訓練の開始だ！
Let's begin!
Time to start defensive training!
R-Retreat!
（ヴァイス）た… 退避！
急げ！ さっさと手を動かせ！
Hurry!
Move your hands!
訓練弾なら 防殻術式でどうにか…
ぐわあっ！
We should be able to block
training shells with magic—
（ターニャ）ん？ おかしいなあ
That's strange.
向こうの手違いか
実弾も含まれているようだ
I guess they screwed something up,
'cause real shells are mixed in there.
そ… そこまでやるかあ～!?
Did...
Did you have to go that far?!
They're coming!
（訓練生）来るぞー！
（訓練生）集中しろ！
Concentrate!
Get down...
（訓練生）伏せろ！
（訓練生）よけろ…
Dodge...
（ヴァイス）
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
お… 終わった…
It's over.
I hope so...
（ヴィーシャ）
だといいけど… んんっ
Those thirty-six hours just flew by, huh?
（ターニャ）
あっという間の36時間だったな
Knowing you're all warriors,
you haven't had enough fun yet, right?
優秀な諸君のことだ
まだまだ遊び足りないだろう？
そこでだ…
諸君は次のポイントへ移動したまえ
And so,
it's time for you to move to the next point.
制限時間は48時間
防殻も飛行術式もなし
You have forty-eight hours.
No defensive spells or flight magic.
If I detect any magic, I'll launch
a magical artillery strike of my own!
魔力反応を感知しだい
私が魔導砲撃を行う
I'll give you one warning.
１つだけ忠告しておくが
くれぐれも注意して行軍するように
Be very careful on your way.
ハァ… はっ 爆撃機だ！
A bomber!
What's that?
（ケーニッヒ）あれを
（ヴァイス）ぐ… 軍用犬!?
A-Army dogs?
We should probably go around them.
（ヴィーシャ）
迂回(うかい)したほうが よさそうですね
と… 特に何も起きないが…
N-Nothing's really happening.
Was she just trying to scare us?
まさか ただの脅し？
It's possible...
ありえる あの大尉殿なら
十分ありえる
Knowing the captain, it's totally possible.
クッソ！ 性根が腐ってやがる！
Damn it.
She's rotten to the core!
ぐっ… ふざけんなあ～！
That bitch!
（ヴァイス）退避！ 退避ー！
Retreat! Retreat!
プハッ！ ハァッ ハァッ…
H-Help me.
（訓練生）た… 助けて 足が…
My leg...
（訓練生）ハァ… ハァ…
（訓練生）ハァッ… ハァッ…
ぐっ うう… ハァ…
Now you're napping during training, huh?
（ターニャ）
訓練中に昼寝とは いい度胸だな！
Want to face a firing squad
for dereliction of duty?
（ターニャ）
職務怠慢で銃殺されたいのか？
（ヴァイス）しっかりしろ おい！
（ターニャ）ん？
Hang in there!
Hey!
（ヴァイス）大丈夫か!?
息をしろ！ おい！
Are you okay? Breathe!
Hey!
N-No...
そ… そんな…
フンッ 雪崩もかわせない無能め
Too useless to even dodge an avalanche—
た… 大尉殿！
いくら何でも それは…
C-Captain, that's going too far!
うっ… ハァッ ハァッ…
H-He came back to life?
い… 生き返った
I can't believe it.
信じられん
That isn't human...
あれは… 人間じゃない
If I try and drop out,
（ノイマン）
下手に脱落などしたら―
I'll meet a fate worse than death.
命どころじゃ…
So that's all of you?
（ターニャ）これで全員か
さて 不測の事態とはいえ
訓練は訓練
Even though this was unexpected,
training is training.
この分では 制限時間内の行軍は
不可能だろう
At this rate, you'll never reach the
designated point before time expires.
If you're going to quit, then now is—
リタイアするなら さっさと…
I will continue the training!
小官は 訓練を継続します！
（訓練生）お… 俺もです！
（訓練生）小官も！
Me, too.
Leave it to me.
And me.
I can keep going.
（訓練生）まだやれます！
（訓練生）やらせてください！
Let me do it.
（ヴァイス）
急げ！ 行軍を完遂するぞ！
Hurry!
We'll finish the march!
Right!
（ヴィーシャ）ええ…
ひっ！ わ… 私も！
I-I'll go, too!
One Month Later
Today, you people are no longer maggots.
本日をもって貴様らは
無価値な うじ虫を卒業する
これより貴様らは
帝国軍魔導師である！
Today, you are Imperial mages.
戦友の絆に結ばれる
貴様らのくたばる その日まで！
You're part of a brotherhood.
From now on, until the day you die,
軍は貴様らの兄弟であり 戦友だ！
wherever you are, every member
of the army is your brother.
Most of you will go to the war zone.
これより諸君は戦地に向かう！
Some of you will not come back.
ある者は二度と戻らない
だが 肝に銘じておけ！
But always remember this:
そもそも帝国軍人は死ぬ
死ぬために我々は存在する！
Imperial soldiers die.
That's what we're here for.
But the Empire lives forever.
だが 帝国は永遠である！
つまり！ 貴様らも永遠である！
And that means you live forever!
故に帝国は 貴様らに
永遠の奮戦を期待する！
Thus, the Empire expects you
to fight forever for it!
Sir, yes, sir!
Imperial Strategic HQ External Bureau
How did this happen?
（ターニャ）
どうして こうなった…
Why did I do that?
私は なぜ
あんなことを…
I don't even remember.
Organization Department
記憶が曖昧だ
訓練中に九五式を
起動しすぎたせいか
Maybe it's because I used
the Type-95 too much in training.
精神汚染検査が必要だな…
I should get examined for
mental corruption...
（ヴィーシャ）デグレチャフ少佐
参謀本部より軍用通信です
Major Degurechaff!
A military communiqué from Strategic HQ.
Understood.
（ターニャ）ご苦労
ハァ… 返信は急ぎと？
Immediate answer required, huh?
はい 既に公用使の方が…
（ターニャ）ん？
Yes, a messenger is waiting outside.
Drawing Room
Congratulations on your promotion,
Major Degurechaff.
（レルゲン）
昇進おめでとう デグレチャフ少佐
I'm Lieutenant Colonel Rerugen
from Strategic Headquarters.
参謀本部のレルゲン中佐だ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
中佐殿のお名前は かねてより
I've heard your name many times.
確か 方面軍の視察中
だったはずでは？
I thought you were inspecting
the forces in theater?
ああ 先日戻った
Yes, I returned a few days ago.
Is something wrong?
（ターニャ）何か？
（レルゲン）いや 何も
No, nothing.
では 私から お伺いいたします
I'll ask you a question, then.
This order says we are to depart at once
for the southeastern garrison,
“直ちに南東管区の駐屯地へ
展開せよ”
“優先度は最優先”とありますが…
and it's given the highest priority level.
貴官の第二〇三航空魔導大隊は
編成を完了したはずだ
I was told your 203rd Aerial Mage Battalion
had been assembled.
ですが まだ訓練大隊も同然
But we're still basically a training battalion.
I'd like six months, at least,
to get everyone trained.
練成には
最低でも半年は頂きたいと
The inspector said
査閲官の話では
即時投入できる戦力だと
聞いている
they had reached the level where
they could be deployed immediately.
All of them are using prototypes of
next-generation Elenium Type-97.
各員が先行量産型の
エレニウム九七式を試験的に運用
And they have completed
adaptation training at 8,000 meters?
高度8,000における順応訓練をも
完遂したそうではないか
戦力均一化のため
それなりの装備を用意したまでです
I just got them the requisite equipment
to balance their fighting strength.
Engineer Schugel owed me a favor.
かのシューゲル技師には
貸しがありましてね
Our military has nothing to spare!
とにかく我が軍には余裕がない
To the west, the Rhine theater is a stalemate,
西方のライン戦線は きっ抗状態
北方もケリがついておらん
and we haven't finished things in the north.
だからこそ分かりませんね
That's why I'm so confused...
なぜ展開先は
南東の駐屯地なのですか？
Why are we being deployed to
the southeastern garrison?
私が各方面を視察し
参謀本部が下した決定だ
It was Strategic Headquarters' decision,
after my inspection of various theaters.
Understood.
（ターニャ）了解しました
If you'll excuse me now.
（レルゲン）では 失礼する
（レルゲン）ああ そうだ
（ターニャ）うん？
Oh, right...
あくまでも個人的な助言だが
せっかく南東方面に展開するのだ
This is just a personal bit of advice,
but since you are heading to
the southeastern garrison,
why not take the opportunity
to learn Dakian?
この機に ダキア語の勉強でも
してみてはどうだ
Dakian?
ダキア…
I see...
（ターニャ）なるほど…
協商連合に共和国―
The Entente Alliance, the Republic,
その上 ダキア公国もか
and now the Dukedom of Dakia?
Imperial Army Southeastern Theater, Military Garrison 5
A message from the southern zone.
（通信兵）
南方管区から通達です
"Emergency."
“緊急 軍団規模ダキア軍
我が国境を侵犯中”
A corps-sized Dakian military unit
has invaded our borders."
Yes.
（通信兵）はい 敵歩兵軍の規模は
４個軍集団 およそ60万と
The enemy infantry comprises approximately
600,000 men, in four army groups.
What's the aerial combat situation?
（ターニャ）航空戦の戦況は？
No information on enemy air strength.
（通信兵）
敵航空戦力の情報は ありません
What?
何？ 通信状況に問題は
Is there a problem with communications?
Everything is normal.
全て正常です
There's no word of an air superiority battle,
制空戦の報告も
入っていませんし―
暗号化されていない敵の通信も
傍受しました
and we've also intercepted
unencrypted communications.
平文だと？ さすがに偽電だろう
Unencrypted?!
Those must be fake...
I can't believe the enemy has no air forces.
敵航空戦力なしなど信じられん
（通信兵）
ですが この空域で拾えるのは―
But all communications we've picked up
in the area are the same type,
全て同様の通信なので
間違いないかと
so that should be accurate.
They aren't encrypting communications,
and they have no aerial forces?
通信の暗号化もせず
おまけに航空戦力もなし
I didn't expect the Dakian Army
to be so inept.
まさか ダキア軍が
それほどまでとはな
Attention!
（ヴァイス）総員 傾注！
Imperial Army 203rd Air Mage Battalion
A message from the battalion commander!
Vice-Commander and 2nd Company Commander
First Lieutenant Matheus Johan Weiss
大隊長より 訓示！
It is time for war, everyone.
Battalion Commander and 1st Company Commander
Major Tanya von Degurechaff
（ターニャ）
さて 大隊諸君 戦争だ
いや 戦争のような
代物の始まりだ
No, something merely similar to war.
（ターニャ）
折しも今日は 私の誕生日だ
Today happens to be my birthday.
それを知ってか
ダキア公国から ご芳情だ
Perhaps the Dukedom of Dakia knew this,
since they've sent me a gift.
ご丁寧なサプライズプレゼントで
実弾演習の標的を頂いた
A wonderful surprise present!
A bunch of targets for
a live-fire training exercise.
1st Company Second-in-Command
Second Lieutenant Viktoriya Serebryakov
You may choose to shoot them
諸君は これを
銃撃してもよいし―
or to destroy them with spells.
術式で爆破してもよい
With guaranteed air supremacy,
3rd Company Commander
First Lieutenant Wilibald Koenig
航空支配が約束されている以上
ある種のマンハント！
this is a man hunt, if anything!
ボーイスカウトを
蹴飛ばすようなものだ
It's like kicking boy scouts about.
4th Company Commander
First Lieutenant Rhiner Neumann
One last thing.
最後に１つ 今回の標的は
一応反撃してくる―
This time, our targets will return fire...
Probably.
…はずだ
（ヴィーシャ）はっ！
まあ 落とされるマヌケは
いないだろうが 留意せよ
Not that any of you are stupid
enough to get shot down,
but keep it in mind.
Very well, gentlemen.
では ジェントルマン諸君
スポーツの時間だ！
It's time for some sports!
（ターニャ）進軍している
ダキア軍の先鋒(せんぽう)集団―
Confirmed sighting of
the Dakian vanguard unit.
約３個師団を確認
Approximately three divisions.
All battalion soldiers, move out.
大隊各位 行動を開始せよ
連中に戦争とは どういうものか
文明の鉄槌(てっつい)をたたき込んでやれ！
Teach them what war is all about.
Bright the hammer of civilization
down upon them!
（３人）了解！
Roger!
（隊長）
進めー！ 列を乱すなー！
Advance!
Don't break formation!
A live-fire exercise is
an apt way to describe this.
実弾演習とは よく言ったものだな
It's basically a bunch of scarecrows.
（ケーニッヒ）敵はカカシ同然
外したら笑い者だな
If we miss, we'll be a laughingstock.
Penetrating spells... Fire!
貫通術式！ てーっ！
（ノイマン）やれやれ
これは負けてられないな
Sheesh, we can't let them beat us.
Follow their lead.
続くぞ！ 砲撃術式 用意！
Prepare artillery spell!
撃てー！
Fire!
Well, this sucks.
（ターニャ）
困ったな やることがないぞ
I have nothing to do.
I was sure this would be a tough battle.
（ヴィーシャ）私は てっきり―
難戦するはめになると
覚悟していたのですが
（ターニャ）フンッ たった
３個師団ごときに緊張とは―
What, scared of a mere three divisions?
ライン帰りとは とても思えん
It's hard to believe you survived the Rhine.
少佐殿 その… ３個師団ですよ
Major, um...
Three divisions is a lot!
I've thought this before, but your idea of
what constitutes a threat is a little...
常々 思うのですが
少佐殿の感性は 少々…
少々？
A little what?
Oh! It's nothing!
いえ 何でもありません！
（ターニャ）
すまん セレブリャコーフ少尉
I'm sorry, Second Lieutenant Serebryakov.
貴官が正しいようだ
Looks like you're right.
Um, I'm sorry?
ええと… はい？
厳密には ５万弱の暴徒ないし
群衆と定義すべきだな
We should define them as a horde or mob,
a little under 50,000 strong.
うっかり 師団と呼べば
なるほど誤解の元だ
I can see why calling them "divisions"
could lead to misunderstandings.
How silly of me...
まったく… 私としたことが
（ターニャ）まあ この世界に
おいては 初めての世界大戦だ
Well, it's the first world war in this world.
Few soldiers truly understand
the threat that air power represents.
航空戦力の脅威など―
ほとんどの軍人が
肌では理解していないわけか
What's that?
あれは… 連中 何をしてる？
What are they doing?
（ヴィーシャ）
恐らく 統制射撃の方陣かと
I believe they're lining up to fire a volley.
You're kidding.
バカな！ 時代錯誤にも程がある
What year do they think this is?
騎兵の時代ではないぞ！ あ…
This isn't the era of cavalry.
ヴァイス中尉？
Lieutenant Weiss?
Why are you falling back?
なぜ距離をとる？
なぜ襲撃隊列を解く？
Why are you breaking attack formation?
Enemy infantry has gotten
into AA formation.
（ヴィーシャ）あれは 敵歩兵が
対空射撃隊列を形成したので―
教範どおり 射程限界に
退避しようとしているのでは…
So as doctrine dictates, he's trying to
fall back to the limits of his range—
（ターニャ）教範だと？
あのマニュアルバカが！
Doctrine? That idiot can't
act without a manual?
空を飛ぶ魔導師に
歩兵の弾が当たるとでも―
Does he really think an infantry
bullet can hit a flying mage?
本気で思っているのか!?
If any mage is shot down by one,
I'll kill him before the enemy does!
あれに撃墜される魔導師がいれば
敵より先に私が殺してやる！
よろしい 我々も参加だ！
Very well! We'll join in, too!
中隊！ 我に続け！
Company, follow me!
（ダキア兵士）て… 敵だー！
（隊長）撃て 撃てえー！
Th-The enemy!
Fire! Fire!
That isn't fair!
ひきょうだぞ！ 降りてこーい！
Come down!
Man, I didn't expect I'd be unable
to even hear the machine guns.
フンッ 重機関銃の発砲音すら
聞こえないとはな
擲弾(てきだん)投下！
Drop grenades!
It's so strange.
おかしな話だ
Aren't we the ones being invaded?
我々が攻められているのでは
ないのかね
まったく困った連中だな
Jeez, what a bunch of morons.
This looks like the invading army's
real HQ, not a decoy.
（ヴィーシャ）偽装ではなく
本物の侵攻軍司令部のようですね
They're broadcasting communications in
the clear, without even dropping output?
（ターニャ）出力も絞らずに
通信を垂れ流すとは
まさか帝国への団体旅行客に
誤射したのではないだろうな
I'm starting to think we actually mowed
down a bunch of tourists, not soldiers.
Y-You bastards!
（将校）き… 貴様ら！
（ターニャ）帝国へ ようこそ！
Welcome to the Empire.
What is the purpose of your visit?
Do you have a visa?
ご入国の目的は？
ビザは お持ちですか？
（将校）ふ… ふざけるなあ！
Sh-Shut up!
ビザは お持ちではない
No visas?
Would you like to enter the country
as prisoners of war, then?
では 捕虜としての
ご入国を希望されますか？
K-Kill them all!
皆殺しにしろー！ 撃てえー！
Fire!
This is a waste of time, huh?
時間の無駄ですね
（ターニャ）ああ
Yeah.
そこの将官以外は撃て
（ヴィーシャ）はっ！
Kill them all, except the commander.
Yes, ma'am.
Presents for Strategic Headquarters.
参謀本部への土産だ
死体以外は
根こそぎ かっさらえ
Take everything but the bodies!
Hey, you.
おい そこ その死体には
ブービートラップを仕込んでおけ
Put a booby trap on that corpse.
Has the unit rendezvoused?
部隊の集結は完了したか
はい 残敵掃討を行いますか
Yes.
Shall we wipe out the remaining troops?
（ターニャ）友軍の航空艦隊は？
Where are our allied air fleets?
もう間もなく 第７航空艦隊が
The 7th Air Fleet will arrive shortly.
As soon as they've reloaded their bombs,
they'll launch a full-scale attack.
再度の爆装が完了しだい
全力出撃とのことです
（ターニャ）ならば
残敵掃討は友軍に任せて―
Then we'll let our allies annihilate
the enemy, and we'll advance.
我々は前進する
はっ！ 目標はどちらへ
Yes, ma'am!
Where will we go?
首都だ
The capital.
The capital?
（ヴァイス）首都… でありますか
（ターニャ）
さらに前へ もっと前へ
Forward... Farther forward.
Let's try this, and see how far we can go.
物は試しだ 行ける所まで
行こうではないか
Our battalion is capable of moving forward.
我々ならば 前に進める
Target sighted.
（ターニャ）目標を発見
Looks like a Republic-backed arms factory.
共和国がテコ入れした
兵器工廠(こうしょう)らしい
It's probably filled with flammables.
さぞ 可燃物が山積みだろうな
But I don't see any air defense.
（ヴィーシャ）
ですが 見たかぎり―
対航空防護は
されていないようですね
（ターニャ）
ああ 連中は１世紀前のパラダイム
No...
They're using last century's paradigm.
今なお 二次元に生きているらしい
They seem to still be living in
two dimensions.
私たちには好機です 襲撃を！
This is our chance. Let's attack.
Second Lieutenant,
少尉 我々は戦時国際法を無視する
野蛮な集団ではないのだぞ
we aren't the kind of barbarians
who'd ignore international wartime law.
人道主義者が定めた法律どおり
敵の工廠だけを破壊し―
In adherence to the laws the ethicists made,
we must destroy nothing but the enemy factory
and warn them to evacuate.
避難勧告も出さねばならん
少佐殿 それでは奇襲の効果が
失われてしまうかと
But, Major, we'll lose the chance
for a surprise attack.
First Lieutenant Weiss...
ヴァイス中尉
I saw this earlier, but you play
by the book a little too much.
貴様 先ほどといい
ちと常識的すぎるぞ
（ヴァイス）あっ…
申し訳ありません！
I-I'm sorry!
Second Lieutenant,
give the warning immediately.
（ターニャ）少尉！
さっさと警告を発しろ
On the international channel,
just like the rules say.
規定どおり
国際チャンネルでだ
But, um... You're sure you want me to?
でも あの…
本当に私でよろしいんですか？
Oh...
Yeah. Looks like it would be better for me to.
確かに私がやったほうが
よさそうだな
We swear that
we will conduct a fair war,
宣誓！ 僕たち 私たちは
国際法にのっとり―
in accordance with international law!
正々堂々 戦争することを誓います
警告します
We warn you now!
The Imperial Army is about to launch
an attack on your military facility!
帝国軍は これより
軍事施設を攻撃します
Wonderful!
すばらしいですね
完全に子供のイタズラと
思っているようです
They seem to think it's a kid's prank!
I didn't know you had
theater experience, Major!
少佐殿は
演劇をやられていたのですか！
Now, everyone,
さて 諸君
国際法上の義務は果たした
we have fulfilled our duty
under international law.
仕事にかかるとしよう
Let's get to work.
All units, prepare ultra-long-range spells!
総員！ 長距離用術式 展開！
Target the Carbelius Weapons Factory!
目標 カルベリウス兵器工廠！
All companies, match your
fire to the commander's.
各中隊は 少佐殿に合わせて
斉射せよ！
In God's name, bring down his wrath on
all who would violate the Fatherland.
神の御名(みな)において
祖国を侵す輩(やから)に鉄槌を
Manifest the miracles of God on Earth.
地上に神の御業(みわざ)を発現せん
Open fire!
総員 てーっ！
直撃16 残りは至近弾！
Sixteen direct hits.
The rest are near hits.
フン 悪くない
Hmm, not bad.
（ヴァイス）ああ… 誘爆です！
Secondary explosions!
（隊員）おお…
（隊員）すごい！
Wow.
Tamaya!
（ターニャ）た～まや～！
Just an expression of joy.
Don't worry about it.
（ターニャ）
ただの感嘆符だ 気にするな
Looks like we owe Dakia big time.
ダキアには足を向けて寝れんな
実弾演習に
協力してもらったばかりか―
Not only did they help with
our live-fire exercise,
訓練後の花火まで
用意してくれるとは
but they even treated us to a
post-exercise fireworks show.
止まれ 目標は達成だ
Halt! We've achieved our objective!
Now, let's head back, my battalion.
さて 帰還するとしようか
大隊諸君